Lise Provost, MSc, MEd, AdmA

liseprovost@videotron.ca www.liseprovost.com

PROFILE

Chartered administrator, member of the Ordre des administrateurs agréés du Québec. Member of the Canadian Public Relations Society and of the Quebec Society of Professional Public Relations Practioners. Expert in all areas of communications and public relations, with 30 years' experience in developing and implementing communications and public relations policies and strategies related to strategic objectives, in the financial and healthcare sectors. Creative, pragmatic, focused on customer service and results oriented, excellent team player. Designed and taught three university courses in the Public Relations program at the Université de Montréal, on crisis management, management and public relations, and communications plans.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Crisis management. Public affairs. Organizing press conferences.
- Managing the image of executives and the organization.
- Managing press relations and acting as a media spokesperson for the organization.
- Proactive approach in dealing with communications issues and the organization's positioning.
- Consulting on communications issues with senior management.
- Developing and implementing internal and external strategic communications plans.
- Organizing annual editorial meetings.
- Applying new trends in press relations and social networks.
- Planning, organizing, directing and overseeing the publishing of Website content, institutional publications, annual reports and corporate videos.
- Organizing large-scale events and managing protocol.
- Developing and managing donation and sponsorship policy.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Ordre des infirmières et infirmiers du Québec (OIIQ)

- Managed public relations for the following issues:
- Raising training standards for the new generation of nurses
- Reducing the number of nurses in long-term residential care centres (CHSLDs)
- Briefs presented to the Parliamentary Commissions on:

Bill 52, end-of-life care – 2013-10-08

Autonomy insurance – 2013-11-14

The right to die with dignity -2012-03-23

Bill 41, Bill to amend the Pharmacy Act – 2011-11-29

Bill 21, Bill to amend the Professional Code – mental health –

2009-06-18 (date the Act was adopted)

LISE PROVOST

- Joint inquiry report by the Collège des médecins du Québec and the OIIQ on the psychiatry department at the Saint-Jérôme CSSS. Press conference.
- OIIQ Annual Convention. Press conference.
- Annual CN-RNC conference of the OIIQ.
- Announced the winners of the Order of Merit and the Grand Prize for clinical innovation.
- Presented the nomination of Danielle Blondeau, 2013 Order of Merit, as the *Le Soleil- Ici Radio-Canada* winner 2013-10-06.
- Presented the nomination of Sylvie Le May, 2013 Florence Award, Nursing research category, named *Personality of the week* by *La Presse Ici Radio-Canada –* 2013-07-08.
- Positioned the nursing profession in L'Actualité, Châtelaine, CV La Presse and Elle Québec.
- Managed internal and external suppliers of professional services.

Chambre de la sécurité financière (CSF):

- Designed and implemented a strategic communications plan.
- Gave *Sécurité financière* magazine a facelift and renewed its production process. Publishing.
- Developed a vast image campaign marketing and advertising fall 2006. 2006 Annual Report. Renewed the CSF website. Developed a letter-writing protocol.
- Managed staff and suppliers of professional services.

Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM):

- Managed public relations and acted as a spokesperson for the announcement of:
 - the first liver transplant from a living donor, a first at the CHUM and in Quebec. the nomination of surgeon Sarah Bellemarre as *La Presse Radio-Canada Personality of the week*, and later as *La Presse Radio-Canada 2005 Personality of the year*, overall category;
 - the official opening of the acute stroke treatment centre;
 - the official opening of the CHUM reimplantation centre;
 - a clinical study on severe depression and its treatment with Omega-3;
 - a clinical study on acute mountain sickness, in climbers on Mount Kilimanjaro.
- Crisis management in transferring Visudyne treatments to a private clinic;
- Organized two days of prostate cancer awareness activities, at Complexe Desjardins, a first at the CHUM in health promotion, and a first in Quebec.
- Developed the communications plan to mark Jeanne Mance's 400th anniversary.
- Managed interns and suppliers of professional services.

Canadian Bankers Association (CBA):

- Organized five community presentations of the *Minding Your E-Business* seminar, concerning electronic security and the protection of personal information. Media Relations. Spokesperson.
- Organized 200 presentations of the *There's Something About Money* seminar on personal finances, at 57 high schools in Quebec, reaching 7,500 students in economics courses and promoting financial literacy for students.
- Involved 25 MNAs in its promotion. Media Relations.

LISE PROVOST

- Trained 159 volunteer bankers to lead the *There's Something About Money* seminar, encouraging them to become involved in their communities.
- Led the *There's Something About Money* seminar in remote regions of Quebec.
- Promoted the *There's Something About Money* seminar on the Radio-Canada *Enjeux* program.
- Managed staff and suppliers of professional services.

General Trust of Canada (GTC) and National Bank Securities (NBS):

- Structured the General Trust public relations department and designed communications policies, programs and strategies.
- Handled the graphic design and production of annual reports for GTC and its subsidiaries, Sherbrooke Trust and Sterling Trust, in Ontario.
- Managed communications relating to the staff reduction at General Trust, from 2,500 to 300 employees, while maintaining employee motivation and a favourable image among internal and external audiences news media, clients and investors.
- Organized two "road shows" to promote mutual funds.
- Designed a communications plan for the National Bank of Canada, on developing the market of businesses headed by women.
- Managed staff and suppliers of professional services.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Public relations consulting Chartered Administrator	2015 to date
Ordre des infirmières et infirmiers du Québec (OIIQ) Press Attaché	2008 to 2014
Chambre de la sécurité financière (CSF) Director of Communications	2006 to 2007
Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM) Senior Advisor, external communications and Co-ordinator, Media Relations	2003 to 2006
Canadian Bankers Association (CBA) Head of Public Relations	2000 to 2003
Lise Provost Relations publiques President	1997 to 2000
General Trust of Canada (GTC) and	1985 to 1997
National Bank Securities Inc. (NBS) Director of Communications (GTC and NBS)	1993 to 1997
Director, Public Relations Department (GTC)	1989 to 1993
Public Relations Officer (GTC)	1985 to 1989

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Ordre des administrateurs agréés du Québec Chartered administrator (AdmA)	2015-03-04
Canadian Securities Institute	
Successfully completed the Canadian Securities Course	2014-12-20
Université Laval	
Master of Science (MSc)	2010 to 2011
Organizational management and development Specialized Graduate Diploma (DESS)	2005 to 2009
Organizational management and development	
Université de Montréal	
Master of Science in Education, Andragogy option (MEd)	1996 to 1998
Université de Montréal and HEC Montréal	1988 to 1992
Bachelor of Science (BSc)	
- Certificate in business management (HEC)	1988
- Certificate in public relations	1990
- Certificate in communication science	1992
École des Hautes Études Commerciales	1986
The practice of public relations	

PARAPROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Member of the Equivalence Review Committee of the Ordre des administrateurs agréés du Québec

Member of the 2014 and 2016 Awards of excellence jury for the Société québécoise des professionnels en relations publiques (SQPRP)

Managed public relations for the IV and V World Congresses of the Secrétariat international des infirmières et infirmiers de l'espace francophone, in Marrakech (2009) and Geneva (2011)

Member of the good neighbours committee of the City of Montréal for the dismantling of the des Pins exchange next to the Hôtel Dieu of the CHUM, 2004 to 2005

Member of the Advisory Committee of the North American Opiate Medication Initiative (NAOMI) - Research into the treatment of heroin addictions -2003 to 2006

Member of the Steering Committee for the "Financial planning for retirement month" of the Régie des rentes du Québec, 2002 to 2003

Member of the fundraising campaign committee for the Théâtre du Rideau vert, 1996 and 1997

Member of the organizing committee for the fundraising campaign and annual benefit galas for Hôpital Sainte-Justine, 1986 to 1989

Member of the fundraising campaign organizing committee for the Cystic Fibrosis Association, 1986, and its very first benefit gala

Member of the Canadian Public Relations Society (CPRS) and of the SQPRP, since 1985

Member of Réseau HEC Montréal since 1988, and of the Université Laval alumni association, since 2009 Member of the Board of the Centre d'accueil Sainte-Domitille, 1986 to 1992